[sweet airy music]
[Ung] "His drawings
that exhibit his emotions
are similar to the doodles
of a child trapped in his own world."
And there you have it, folks,
my entire life summed up in one sentence.
I took pity on you.
It seemed like
your life was so meaningless
that you abandoned things so easily.
What would your life be
if you kept living it like that?
[Ung] Honestly,
what he said hit home hard.
WITH UNG
THE UNBEARABLE LIGHTNESS OF BEING
Hmm, I wanna live an easy life.
You know, just peaceful and carefree.
[chuckles]
[Yeon-su] Excuse me, ma'am?
[Yeon-su] What's your school ranking?
[Ung] I'm 267th.
How many students are here?
267 students.
[breathes in sharply]
Drawing is just like a hobby to me.
What I want,
is to bask in the sun during the day
and to lay underneath a lamp at nighttime.
A life of stress just isn't for me.
- [teacher] What's wrong with you?
- I can draw a new one.
[professor] Choi Ung,
don't you have any ambition?
[Ung] Someone needs this chance
more than I do. Give it to them.
[Ji-ung] Don't pull back.
I want your innermost thoughts
about your work, your process,
about your life as an artist,
you can talk about
your future plans and goals.
I don't really have any.
[Ung] That's how I lived.
Always been that way.
Hey Ung, you're very lucky. You're so
young, but you already have a restaurant.
[woman] Are you gonna
work here when you grow up?
- Of course he will, it's named after him.
- What do you wanna be?
[woman] Money's not gonna be a problem.
You're a lucky little boy. Bye!
[Ho] That's it.
You hold your spoon just like this.
And then, you get a good spoonful of rice.
That's all you have to do,
eat well and be healthy. Okay? Like this.
[Yeon-ok chuckles]
- There. That's it.
- He's right.
Don't worry about a thing,
just do whatever you want in life.
Because that is all
we'll ever want from you, understand?
- [Ho] Exactly.
- [parents gasping]
- [Yeon-ok] Oh, my goodness. Wow.
- Good boy.
[Ung] Some moments,
you don't have to do anything.
Sometimes it's just the right choice.
[both sobbing]
Know your place in life. Especially
if it's borrowed from someone else.
Ung, do you think you can draw Mommy?
Ung, do you think
you can draw Daddy first?
- [Yeon-ok] No. Ung--
- Ung, can you please draw Daddy first?
- Pretty please? Come on.
- Oh, come on.
[Ung] It's best not to be greedy…
- you just can't be selfish.
- [Ho] I'm easier to draw.
Ung, when are you ever gonna draw me, huh?
Ung, when are you finally
gonna draw your Dad, huh?
[Yeon-ok] Can you draw me, please?
You know what? I'll draw you. I can!
- What in the world do you know?
- Oh please. I'm a total natural.
- Who do you think he takes after?
- [Yeon-ok] Me.
Wow. That's a good pose. Hold on.
Good. Just stay still.
Yep, that's a great angle.
You look beautiful. Let me do this.
[Ung] That's why
I wanted to be a good son,
at least one this perfect family deserved…
[Ho] No, stop blinking.
["Drawer" by 10CM playing]
[Ung] …not the son
abandoned by his father.
[Ho] Thanks to those groups of customers,
it's getting way too hectic in here.
- Here you go.
- [Ho] Hectic nights, what a delight.
[Ung] That means that,
if I don't do anything,
maybe I'll turn out all right.
[reporter] This one's come in just now.
A series of studies have established
that one's genes
can have more of an effect
towards determining one's personality,
at least more than the environment
that a person is raised in.
In order to support this theory,
gene-mapping researchers in the US,
through a funded research,
are currently looking for the genes
that are likely to determine one's per--
- [Ho] Well, honestly, I don't know either.
- [Yeon-ok] Me neither.
[Ung] Deep inside, I was afraid that I
might inherently be a worthless person.
That's why I decided to play ignorant,
pretending like I never cared all along.
But in the end,
I couldn't escape it after all.
It's like fate.
I ended up becoming
the person I was meant to be,
worthless. Worthless man,
trapped in a worthless life.
EPISODE 16
OUR BELOVED SUMMER
ENROLLMENT GUIDE SCHOOL
OF ARCHITECTURE, ENSA, PARIS
Yeon-su, I want you to come with me.
I'm not taking this lightly at all.
I've thought this through for a while.
I know this all seems so sudden to you.
Can you just trust me on this
and follow me?
So this is something
you've been planning for a while now?
I've been pathetic
the entire time since we met.
That's why I thought…
It's about time I start anew.
However…
I need you by my side.
I can't do this on my own.
But this… this means
you'll be going far away for a while--
That doesn't matter. I need you.
You know that.
I'm asking you to come with me
and stay by my side through this.
I know you know
that I'm a huge mess.
[soft gentle music]
I'm gonna think about it.
Give me some time first.
It's something
I have to give some real thought.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I mean, after all, first time
you wanted to do something.
[soft gentle music]
[sighs]
Bet I sounded more pathetic than usual.
You didn't.
And I never thought for once
that you were ever pathetic.
You've achieved more than I have,
so shut it.
[gentle music]
Sorry? What did you just say?
I said, I'd like for you to work
at our headquarters up in Paris.
I've recently just been
assigned to go there
and I need to assemble a new team for it.
And you were
the first one I thought of who would fit.
I looked through
all of the past projects you headed,
and they were quite fascinating.
Great. But why…
You're someone that I need, Ms. Kook.
That's all there is to it.
So once again,
I'd like you to come with me.
You'll find the terms are quite favorable,
along with the reason
I'm trying to recruit you.
That is, because I know
how competent you are at this.
[chuckles softly]
Thank you very much.
I didn't expect you of all people
to make an offer like this so…
I'm not sure what to think.
Am I still a sociopath to you?
[chuckles]
[Do-yul] That's all, I guess.
Anyway, I need to take my dog for a walk.
Give it some real thought and let me know.
[I-hun] It's a good opportunity.
Actually, Mr. Jang came to me first and
talked to me about it, before meeting you.
He sure has a keen eye
for competent workers, I'll give him that.
But anyway, don't ponder about it too much
and just say "Yes," understand?
- I can't… I still--
- [I-hun] Yeon-su.
Now listen, I'm saying this
as a friend who cares about you.
I don't want you to miss this chance.
So take it.
[I-hun] You've more than earned this.
I saw how hard you worked to get this far.
So this time around,
put yourself first before anyone else
and don't look back. Just try it.
Also, this time,
try following your heart. Got it?
[soft pensive music]
How could he fire me just like that?
I'm gonna file a complaint
for wrongful termination.
I'm gonna expose
everything wrong that he's done
and then I'm gonna sue his ass to death.
You're not going to do any of that.
[sniffling]
Choi Ung, you dirty scumbag.
[Eun-ho] That guy
can't do anything without my help.
So let's see
how well he does from here on.
What can you do though?
He really wants to go.
If you're really that sad,
just tag along with him.
Can you believe
he didn't even bother inviting me to go?
He could have at least tried asking.
And then I would have reluctantly
given in eventually.
I can't believe him. Why?
What would you even
do in France if you go?
If he's gonna go there to study,
why would he ask you to tag along?
He made the decision for your sake.
No, look. He told me to live my life.
The nerve of that guy.
Exactly whose life does he think
I've been living for all this time?
What does he think? That I can't do
anything without him to order me around?
What are you gonna do without him?
Well, obviously…
I can do…
[sobbing]
I can't do anything without him. Oh, God…
[sobbing dramatically]
DAEHAN BANK
Okay, now what?
[gasping shout]
[Sol-i] Wait!
Hey, tell me. What is it?
Come on.
[sobbing loudly]
- [Sol-i] What are these? Tears or snot?
- My severance pay…
Your nose is running like crazy.
- It's my severance pay…
- It's your what?
- My severance pay…
- What about it?
Is he not giving you any?
He gave me way too much…
- [cheeky music]
- [dramatic sobbing]
[gasping shout]
[Sol-i] No way!
[Eun-ho crying]
Eun-ho.
If you don't have any plans,
like in the future, what do you say
if we… start a business together?
[suddenly stops crying]
Don't be absurd, Sol-i.
I don't do business with others.
Seeing as I already got a friend discount,
how about a celebrity discount?
I'll give you
a bigger discount if you want.
I was just kidding.
You should stop saying things that
can devalue your work. It's not right.
Impossible.
They aren't even that great to begin with.
Wait. So by extension
are you trying to say
that I probably
have terrible taste in art?
Nah-uh, not what I meant.
Do you wanna know the reason
why I like your drawings?
The more I looked at them,
the more I realize
why your drawings always gave me
the feeling of comfort.
Those crooked lines
let off more than you realize.
[NJ] They made me wonder if by chance
you were just as insecure as I was.
Your stubbornness
to only draw unchangeable objects,
deep down I always wondered
if perhaps you were just as lonely as me.
But then I look at your final work,
it all just comes together.
It gives me this warm feeling.
It looks stable.
As if it was drawn by…
someone a lot more resilient than others.
Surprisingly, that comforts me.
It's as if you're telling me
that I can become just like you.
That's it. That's basically
my critique of your work.
So don't mind the others
and listen to someone who understands.
After all, I'm your biggest buyer.
I appreciate it.
You know,
somehow it's actually very comforting.
I just realized
how close we've already become
seeing how we've been
comforting each other.
[both chuckle]
So anyway,
I'm quite sad to be saying goodbye.
Studying abroad
makes you feel really lonely.
I'll be fine. Yeon-su's coming along.
Oh, really?
Should be obvious
that I can't live without her.
Oh.
You're a lucky guy.
That just proves
how much she really loves you.
[NJ] She chose your life over hers.
Not an easy thing,
dedicating yourself to someone.
That's quite the sacrifice she's making.
Grandma.
Hmm?
Are you really going to be okay
without me here?
Of course. I'll be just fine.
Wow, you didn't even think about that.
That kinda hurts.
My life's simple. I'll be busy
spending time with my old friends.
I know, but what if you collapse again
and no one's around to help you?
As long as I take my blood pressure meds
regularly, they said I'd be fine.
Oof.
I'm fine. Just go.
And stop worrying about me.
You follow your heart for a change.
Think of it as a favor. You got that?
Come on. Let's go.
Goodness. Let's go.
[gentle music]
[NJ] She chose your life over hers.
Not an easy thing,
dedicating yourself to someone.
I mean, after all, first time
you wanted to do something.
[gentle pensive music]
[sighs]
Also, this time,
try following your heart. Got it?
I'm fine. And stop worrying about me.
You follow your heart for a change.
I should start following my heart?
[gentle pensive music]
DAILY BEER
- [Dong-il] Thank you very much.
- My pleasure, sir.
Do it.
I can't think of
a single reason why I should.
Because that's exactly what we do.
Recording these moments in people's lives.
We're always explaining
how priceless that is.
Part of our job is to convince them
how important those memories are.
So what makes you so different?
The difference is,
there's nothing worth recording.
[Ji-ung] You know what?
I just don't get it.
My ghost of a mom suddenly comes back
out of nowhere, saying that she's dying.
And now she wants me to film her.
Why now? What am I supposed to do?
Why should I even consider…
What makes her think I'd do it for her?
After all this time, why would I do that?
Simple, you do it for yourself.
You're the one who has to live with it.
Someone has to be able
to carry that memory forward,
so that it doesn't fade away.
You don't do it, no one else will.
[Ji-ung sighs]
Hey.
Do you even have a portrait of her
you can use for her funeral?
Funny, right?
Your job is to film other people,
yet you don't have
a single photo of your mom.
I didn't have any photos of my mom either,
except for this one.
It was some group photo
with people I don't know.
She was surrounded by all these
other people and smiling from ear to ear.
But I'm grateful,
because at least I have that.
I look at it every now and then,
when I think about her.
[soft emotional music]
Regardless, I don't know
the entire story between you and your mom.
You can resent her or you can forgive her,
but that can wait for now.
Someone is dying.
Someone you clearly think about.
[Dong-il] Don't waste this moment
by doing nothing.
That's all.
[soft emotional music]
- Ung.
- Hmm?
I was thinking this evening…
do you wanna go to Sol-i's later?
Okay.
[gentle music]
Okay. I understand.
And I respect your decision.
[puffs out breath]
Oh, come on.
The owner of this restaurant
sure makes her customers uncomfortable.
Well, only for this one specific customer,
since he's so busy, he rarely visits us.
[both chuckle]
You must be busy with your girlfriend,
so what brings you all the way over here?
No reason.
I just missed your food, that's all.
Oh. I'm not a kid anymore.
You should eat well
whenever something's worrying you.
I never said I was worried.
You don't have to. I'm your mom.
Oh, my little son.
I can't believe you're all grown up.
You knew all along…
Hmm.
Of course I knew.
…that I knew about it?
After… did that change anything?
Why would that change anything?
It's irrelevant.
You're my son no matter what happens.
I've been blessed. And I knew right away,
you've always been my son, Ung.
Thank you for being my son.
I'm so grateful
seeing you grow up into a wonderful man.
I…
I was afraid…
that I wouldn't take after you and Dad.
[breathing shakily]
[emotional vulnerable music]
I was afraid I wouldn't turn out
to be a good person like you.
I was hoping I'd become good enough…
at least good enough in your eyes.
[Ung] I was so scared that I would…
end up disappointing you.
That's what I'm most afraid of.
[sighs]
What can I say, Ung?
Your dad and I,
we were never disappointed in you.
[sniffles]
Ever since the moment we saw you
and embraced you in our arms,
we have loved every single part of you.
[emotional vulnerable music]
[both chuckling]
Mom.
Yes?
[Ung] Right now,
I just wanna become
a better version of myself.
You know, all I wish is that…
you will at least be able
to get some good sleep now.
[chuckles]
Hurry and eat your food. You're gonna
miss out if you let it go cold.
[producer] NJ, congratulations,
this is your last interview.
We've prepared the questions right here.
We made a copy for you.
You can go through them and check,
in case you wanna make sure.
First question there, we were wondering
if there was a specific reason you
chose this place to shoot for
your last interview. All right keep it up.
Excuse me, sir,
I have a small favor to ask you.
Sure.
What is it?
[sighs softly]
- Oh, have you been here long?
- No, not really.
[Yeon-su] Really cold out there.
Yeah, it's freezing.
[groans]
I told you
to wear thicker clothes, didn't I?
I warmed up my hands for you.
- Can you feel it?
- Hmm.
But I'm really fine.
You'll get cold again.
That's okay.
Have you…
made up your mind?
Hmm.
[sighs]
[gentle music]
I knew it. You're always waiting.
[Yeon-su groans]
Grandma.
Do you remember what you told me?
That I should stop
enduring everything on my own.
To go out there and make friends,
follow what my heart wants,
and just enjoy life.
So this time around I'm…
I'm going to make the bold choice
and follow what my heart's wanted
all along.
[Yeon-su] And do you know what I realized?
That all this time,
that's how I've been living.
I have no idea
where I got the notion that I was alone.
Honestly…
there was never a time when I was alone.
["Summer Rain" by Sam Kim playing]
Hey. I'm here!
- Welcome to…
- Hey!
Hey…
[Sol-i] Hey, I came up with a scenario.
Give me an objective review.
I've been writing this for a while…
What do I do?
He asked for my number in public.
The title is Point of Omniscient Psycho…
…he looked pretty sincere, too.
What do you think? Should I go for it?
I have an offer and I want you
to think about it carefully.
I-hun, I'm a little too busy.
I can't make--
Work with me. I wanna hire you.
I'm sorry, like I said,
I'm a little too busy.
I'm not just
asking for your help, Yeon-su.
I am recruiting you, as in officially.
It's a business that I'm starting
and the terms aren't so bad.
Right. Also, you get a signing bonus.
[chuckles]
Just a sec. I never asked for your help,
why the sudden offer?
'Cause I know that eventually
you'll land a job at a big company,
only a matter of time, really.
[I-hun] I know that my company is small.
But you're going to be getting
a lot of work done,
I'll be getting my money's worth for sure.
I'm saying…
this will be the biggest investment
that I've ever made,
but I know that it's worth it.
So just read all this through.
If you change your mind,
just call me. Okay?
Oh. Thanks for the coffee.
["Summer Rain" softly playing]
CONTRACT
RUN AND GOOK YEON-SU'S AGREEMENT
RUN, SINSAMALL
ON AND OFFLINE PR PLANS
- [I-hun] Yeon-su.
- Yeah?
Can you include this part right here?
It's important that we put that in there.
You got it? Okay?
We need to collaborate.
We need to communicate more.
RUN
COMMUNICATION GROUP
[Ye-in] Ms. Kook!
Hey, Ms. Kook!
Your presentation was awesome. Oh, my God!
It was such a clean-cut
and direct presentation.
I think we got this in the bag,
I can tell! You're the best!
[I-hun] I'm not even surprised anymore.
Seriously, when are you gonna stop
getting better? Do you even have a limit?
[all laughing happily]
Am I right? She never stops!
Just keeps setting the bar.
- Get-together tonight?
- Sure thing!
[laughing and cheering]
[Yeon-su] I thought
my life was pretty dull for some reason.
But I have so many good memories.
I never realized.
The only one
who made my life seem pathetic…
it was me all along.
Grandma.
["Summer Rain" continuing]
[sighs]
I'm not going,
Ung.
For the first time,
I'm finally beginning to enjoy my life.
I can clearly see the path I took.
That's why
I wanna live this life a bit longer.
I used to think that
I had no option
but to push on with this life I was given.
But now…
I think this was the life
I wanted in the first place.
That's why…
I wanna live my life
with no regrets and keep going.
Say something, will you?
I was thinking about how long it'd take.
For what?
The time it'll take
for me to earn what I really want.
How long it'd take for me to deserve you.
What do you mean, deserve me?
You're an exceptional person, Yeon-su.
You're way beyond my league.
But me…
I've just been wasting way too much time.
But you know what?
I've finally realized
what it is I need to do.
What I really wanted to do,
what I desire most of all.
I know who I am now.
[gentle music]
And that's why…
I think…
It's okay, Ung.
[gentle music]
You can go.
Everyone's gonna be okay.
[soft sweet music]
I promise, it won't take too long.
Hmm.
I'm not gonna change either.
I will come back, I swear.
Hmm.
So please, just…
I'm asking you to wait for me.
[soft sweet music]
Why are you just standing there?
Come over here and sit down.
We were always so distant,
so I'm fine over here.
How can you suddenly think
it's okay to approach me now?
It's unfair…
to just die like this all alone.
If I died
without even leaving a single trace…
that I ever existed…
that's just unfair.
You're selfish
just like you've always been.
That's what I'll be…
horrible until the day I die.
[Ji-ung's mom] I understand.
You don't have to care about me.
Maybe it's okay to feel a little sorry
just a little…
and pay a visit
from time to time.
[mild scoff]
[breathes in sharply]
[Ji-ung] It doesn't make any sense.
Why would you even come back
if that's what you wanted?
You want things to be just the same?
You should've never
showed your face again.
[soft shaky breath]
Can you please say something?
Say something.
Anything.
[Ji-ung's mom] Back then…
I couldn't handle it,
the sickness I had in my heart.
I didn't have a choice, I just didn't.
I was afraid that
eventually, being with you…
you'd be just as miserable.
At times…
I would see your face out there…
so bright and full of life.
And the thing I feared the most…
was that I'd ruin you
and drag you down with me.
[sobs]
I was so scared. That's why…
That's why I couldn't…
I couldn't bear embrace you.
["Home" by Janet Suhh playing]
I not going to forgive you.
I can't.
Not ever.
I know.
The suffering you're going through…
can never justify what you did to me.
I know.
All right?
You were a mother.
And me…
I was just a little kid.
[Ji-ung] How could a mother
do that to her own son?
You're right.
How could you suddenly just appear
and tell me that you're dying?
[Ji-ung] You hurt me.
I'll never forgive you.
It's not gonna happen.
[crying softly]
Okay.
But maybe…
who knows, one of these days…
I might just
change my mind out of nowhere.
[Ji-ung] So please just…
I want you to fight to live.
Better now than never,
you and I can start with a clean slate.
We don't have to keep relying
on other people anymore.
Let's just live an ordinary life together…
you know, like everyone else.
["Home" playing]
[Ung] We were 29 years old. Headstrong.
That was the time
we all took charge of our lives.
And then, I had to get ready
to leave for abroad.
[sighs]
I told my parents right away too.
By the end of the month, I'll be leaving.
[Ho breathes angrily]
[Yeon-ok] Honey.
[Ung] Surprisingly,
my dad got really upset
and refused to see me for a month.
Come on, he always nagged me
when I was around.
[email beeping]
YOU'VE LEFT ME,
BUT I'M SENDING THIS FOR YOU
Eun-ho was also mad at me.
And he sent me a 60-page document
on how to survive.
Oh, Ji-ung has also been very busy.
He's being filmed now, ironically.
I'm… uhm…
[Ji-ung] So I was…
I'm sorry.
Can you repeat the question again?
I was asking you to please share with us
some of the most memorable moments
you've had with her, Mr. Kim.
All right.
Cue.
[Ji-ung] Most memorable, huh?
Oh. I think
every last Saturday of the month…
we'd go to the marketplace
every afternoon and have some tteokbokki.
I remember my mom was always busy.
That was the only day she had off.
[chuckles softly]
We'd go to the market,
hold hands and walk around.
It made me happy, doing that.
[Ung] Well, the guy who always
talked about being an observer,
finally knows what it's like
to be on the other side.
[NJ] You've all seen me from the surface
but I hope that you're not forgetting…
[Ung] Oh, NJ, as usual,
is causing her agency even more headaches.
Being in front of a camera, I always
wanted to show you my cheerful side.
[Ung] A 30-minute no hold barred,
unedited footage
broadcasted
out of the blue with no warning.
So please be kind to one another.
[Ung] The public seems
to be bashing her once again,
but now she's also receiving
just as much support.
As for Yeon-su and myself…
[Yeon-su] Ung.
[laughs]
- Did you get cold?
- Nope.
- Were you waiting for a while?
- Not even.
Let's go.
[Ung] We made the best
of our time together.
["Red String Of Fate"
by Kim Kyung Hee playing]
[both chuckling]
Just us, every single day.
Tell me, did you really rehearse
spraying me with water every day?
Originally, I was going to pour
a bucket over you, so you got lucky.
Unless you dump me again.
Now I'm really curious
if you'd really do it.
No. I take that back.
And enough of that. Don't do it again.
No more what-ifs and stuff.
Okay, I promise. But can I ask you
one last what-if question?
- No!
- What if we…
[laughing]
- [Ung] Every single day.
- What if we suddenly…
- [Ung] Stop it!
- [Yeon-su laughing]
["Red String Of Fate" continuing]
[Ung] It was perfect.
However, I had to go.
The day of my flight came pretty quick.
Oh, my God, Ung, we're screwed!
- [Ung] What? What is it?
- This is bad. I'm telling you.
- This is a disaster, Ung.
- [Ung] What?
- What's wrong?
- Our tank is low.
[Ho] And we're gonna be late
if we have to stop for gas.
You can't be late for your flight,
they'd leave without you,
- so how about you just don't go?
- Come on, Dad.
I can see you've got a full tank,
which is rare.
Plus, we have some time to spare.
[sighs]
Right. I almost forgot,
I have to stop by somewhere.
[Ung] Wait for me outside.
Hey, Son. Go wherever
you need to go. Don't come back.
Don't come back
so you can miss the flight.
I'll say there was an accident, huh?
Not gonna take long.
[Ung] There was one more thing I had to do
before I could embark on my new journey.
I had to finally confront the past…
the one that had haunted me.
I wanted to just tell him
once and for all…
there's no need to keep hurting himself,
there's no more need to avoid me,
or feel sorry for ourselves.
[soft music]
We've done that more than enough,
it's time for us to let go of each other.
[Yeon-su] And just like that,
Ung had left around the end of winter.
I was fine. Same as usual.
You see, I'm a lot more mature
when it comes to relationships.
Where are you, my little Ung? My baby Ung.
I miss you so much…
I'm begging you,
can someone please call the cops?
I want this psycho behind bars,
she's scaring off all my customers.
[screaming]
Ung! Where are you?
- [Yeon-su] Of course, naturally…
- Someone find my Ung!
[Yeon-su] …there were a few little days
when I missed him a bit too much.
What if a female student
who lives right next to you,
knocks on your door, you answer,
then she asks for butter
or whatever it is they use as an excuse.
I'm gonna lock the door
and then call the police.
Good answer.
[chuckles]
Okay, what if something else happened.
You're busy somewhere studying
and a female student
tells you she speaks Korean
and offers to teach you French.
What are you gonna do then?
I'll show her my translating device.
- Good. You're doing well, Mr. Choi.
- [chuckles]
Then what if you went to a coffee shop…
[Yeon-su] Things are going
fairly smoothly, all things considered.
Oh, Ye-in, can you please share
the presentation materials
- with the rest of the team?
- Yes, ma'am, it's done.
Hey, what's going on, you guys? Huh?
How are you all so great at your jobs?
It's unbelievable.
- I don't know what to do with you anymore.
- [all chuckling]
I feel so ecstatic,
I can't hold myself back.
- What do you say--
- [Yeon-su] No get-together today.
I didn't even say anything.
In case you forgot,
we just had one yesterday.
If you keep this up,
I'll have to ban get-togethers again.
"I'll ban get-togethers again." Geez.
[chuckles]
Then how about
tomorrow evening? How's that?
Tomorrow is Saturday.
Okay. This coming Monday then,
after work, sounds good, right?
We have a meeting.
All of us are… Well, not you, though.
Oh.
[chuckles]
Without me right?
[I-hun] You already organized a meeting.
Was everyone informed
that I wouldn't be attending?
[Yeon-su] We focused on our lives
and did our best with what we had.
And before we knew it,
time flew by in the blink of an eye.
[sighs]
You're being too careless.
Why'd you have to drink so much?
You're not exactly at home, you know.
Do you have any idea
how dangerous it could have been? Huh?
- [Yeon-su] Of course…
- What would do if…
…there were times
when we argued over and over.
[scoffs]
So you're not
gonna call me all day, are you Ung?
Then I might just not pick up,
even if you try calling me.
[phone buzzing]
Yeah, hello? Ung?
[Ung] Hmm. Been waiting a while?
No, I wasn't waiting.
Of course not. I wouldn't. As if. No way.
[Ung chuckling]
Sorry. Been moving a lot the entire day.
Hey you, communication is the core
of a long-distance relationship.
If this keeps happening,
I'll be really hurt.
It's gonna cause a misunderstanding.
[Ung] I understand. Are you going home?
Hmm. And you? Going home?
To sleep?
Have you been sleeping well lately?
And also, how's your eating schedule?
[Ung] Don't you ever
get tired of asking me that?
Do you? Why? Are you getting tired of me?
[Ung] No, that's not what I meant.
Calm down.
Geez, Yeon-su. You know,
you've been sulking a lot lately.
Yeah. I've become pettier than ever.
[sighs]
If only I'd known it'd be like this
I would've hidden
your passport when you flew in last time.
[Ung chuckles]
You've become a lot cuter too.
[sighs]
I miss you so much, Ung.
What? Why aren't you saying anything?
[Ung] Yeon-su.
Now that I think about it,
there was something I forgot to tell you.
What is it?
[audio falls away]
What did you say?
[Ung] You heard me.
No, I didn't.
I couldn't hear you properly,
so you have to say it again.
[Ung] I love you.
Do you…
Do you even realize how long
it took for you to finally say that?
Why didn't you… How come I've never
heard you say that to me before?
[Ung] I love you, Yeon-su.
You're such an idiot.
You know that, right?
You supposed to say that in front of me.
You're unbelievable.
[Ung] All right. Fine.
Turn around and I will.
["The Giving Tree"
by Lee Seung Yoon playing]
You…
Kook Yeon-su.
I love you.
What are you doing here?
I missed you so much,
so I couldn't help it, I had to see you.
But this is way too sudden.
I didn't have a choice,
I had to tell you right now.
[sighs in relief]
Hey, I know the feeling, I can't handle
long-distance relationships.
I know that.
That's why you should finish your studies.
[Yeon-su] Otherwise,
can't you skip a year and come back?
- I don't know.
- [Yeon-su sniffles]
That's why I've been telling you.
You should study hard
and try to graduate early.
You can't keep
coming back and forth just to visit.
It'll take ages for you
to just finish your studies.
Hey, Yeon-su, are you
seriously nagging me right now?
I'm not nagging,
I'm only saying this for our sake.
["The Giving Tree" continuing]
[Yeon-su] And there were also times…
that I'd classify as
unbelievably phenomenal.
That's how we were.
["The Giving Tree" continuing]
And that's the reason we were able
to stay strong all those years.
And just like he promised from the start,
he did it. And it didn't
take him too long, like he said.
2 YEARS LATER
[Eun-ho] Sol-i.
Sol-i!
- Hey, you.
- [Sol-i] Say what?
- Don't "Hey you" me, you rude prick.
- We need to hurry up. We're already late.
Did Ung's parents leave already?
Yeah, they left ages ago.
We need to double time.
Step aside.
[Eun-ho groans]
[cheeky music]
- Have you been working out?
- What? That was nothing.
They're pretty light.
Wrap it up and come out.
- I'll go start the car.
- [Sol-i] Okay.
[sighs in disbelief]
I can't believe that kid has me
wrapped around his damn finger.
He definitely has a crush on me,
why won't he make his move?
It's been ages. Why?
[Eun-ho] Come out already.
Sheesh.
You're like a pesky little child.
Mr. Choi's parents
are such generous people, aren't they?
They must've spent a hefty sum already
if they've been donating regularly.
You're right.
I didn't know about it either,
now I have more respect for those two.
And Ms. Kook, is she going to be there?
[chuckles softly]
I'm sure.
Will you be okay? After all,
she is the girl that broke your heart.
[chuckles]
Yep, and you never fail to remind me.
Thanks, I almost forgot.
Can't wait for the next reminder.
People are saying
you're starting to become like me,
but maybe don't overdo it. Okay?
- I need to say something.
- What now?
And I'm only gonna say this
because you seem
to be doing a lot better now.
Just so you know, I like you.
I'm only saying this because people
are saying I'm becoming more like you.
And since you
never confessed your love to her,
I'm not gonna be like you.
[surprised exhale]
That's all. Just saying, you know.
[soft uplifting music]
[chuckles softly]
MUSIC LIBRARY
BOOK DONATION WITH UNG
TWOO TWIT
THE RED DOG OF THE DARK
WITH UNG
[classical piece playing]
- [Yeon-ok] Over here. Come on, guys!
- Come on, let's go.
Sol-i, I'm hungry.
What are we eating, huh?
What the heck are you asking me that for?
Don't you wanna go on a date?
BOOK DONATION WITH UNG
Okay then, I'm ready.
[Sol-i] So that's why
he's been working out.
[Ho] Okay. It's very nice to meet you.
I'm sorry I'm a little embarrassed,
because this isn't really my thing.
I believe everyone should be doing this
and as a member of society,
I'm just doing my part.
It's a small contribution to help out.
[Ho] Oh, my goodness, I'm so embarrassed.
Uh… My son loved books.
Which is why we had so many.
As a boy, he'd always be reading.
And we would go on for hours.
He takes after me.
- I hope all kids would have the chance--
- Hey, Ung.
[Ho] Come on, not again!
[Yeon-ok] You're so late.
I told you to come early and help out.
I've been carrying these
since this morning, trust me.
- Is that true?
- [Ung] Yes.
It always turns into a blooper
and we need to do a retake
whenever Ung pops in.
Hey, you get some sleep?
How long do you usually marinate pork?
I don't know. For eight hours?
Well, I slept for ten hours.
Even longer than marinated pork.
- Oh, what a good boy!
- [Yeon-su] Hello everyone!
- [Ho] Hey, Yeon-su.
- Yeon-su.
I told you not to go, what are you doing?
You should be resting on weekends.
I'm okay. I should help out anyway.
So where do I put this down?
Upstairs.
[Ho] Yeon-su, just put yours
on top of Ung's. He'll handle it.
Hurry, help her.
[chuckles]
BOOK DONATION WITH UNG
[cheerful bubbly music]
[yawns loudly]
Don't you think
you're just oversleeping nowadays?
Once the exhibition begins,
I won't be getting enough.
So I should sleep while I still can.
[Ung groans]
How long is this gonna take?
Don't be lazy. Stop putting them wherever.
Make sure to put them in the right order.
I'll be watching you.
[cheerful bubbly music]
Somehow this all feels too familiar.
Reminds you of high school, doesn't it?
Isn't that memory
a little too old to remember?
Not really. Still vivid in my head.
As if it only happened yesterday.
Frankly, same here.
[chuckles softly]
Tell me the truth for once.
About?
About you having a crush on me
when we first met.
[scoffs, breathes in sharply]
There you go, manipulating
your memory for your benefit again.
Nah-uh!
Don't deny it, I could see it
in your eyes. It was obvious.
[scoffs]
Yeah, don't make me laugh.
You sure you're not the one
who fell in love with me at first sight?
That's why you followed me around, right?
When was it that I saw you
for the first time?
Was it the first day of filming?
- Hey.
- Or was it before that?
I know you're just pretending
like you don't remember when it was.
Hey, we're supposed
to be putting books in.
What have you been doing?
Why would you doodle on that?
You're not a kid.
I LOVE EARLY SUMMER
LEE NA-EUN
What did you draw in this?
[Ung] Unforgettable.
Everyone has one
from a certain time in their life.
["Christmas Tree" by V playing]
Those memories you cherish so much
every waking moment
will last you for a lifetime.
Kook Yeon-su.
Our year hasn't even ended yet…
♪ Your light's the only thing
That keeps the cold out ♪
♪ Moon in the summer night ♪
♪ Whispering of the stars ♪
…and our life has barely begun.
[Ung] Marry me, Yeon-su.
EPILOGUE
Ready to film?
What? What did you just say?
You're gonna have to, it's all your fault.
What are you nuts? It's not happening.
Your last documentary
is back from the dead and popular.
Why the hell'd you have to get married?
Too bad, now they all
wanna watch your married life.
Are you crazy? Aren't we ever
gonna have some sort of privacy?
Hey, what do you take us for,
a couple of pushovers you can boss around?
- Hello everyone.
I'm Choi Ung.
I'm Kook Yeon-su.
[chuckle softly]
One, two, three.
[both] So, we're married now.
[chuckles]
["Christmas Tree" by V playing]